Register of the United States. House Republican Research Committee. Task Force on Terrorism and Unconventional Warfare reports
Hoover Institution Archives
United States. House Republican Research Committee. Task Force on Terrorism and Unconventional Warfare reports
1989-1994
91058
United States. House Republican Research Committee. Task Force on Terrorism and Unconventional Warfare.
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Contains reports relating to global implications of terrorist activities, guerrilla operations, and regional conflicts throughout the world.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1991
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Subcommittee of the Republican Party delegation in the United States House of Representatives.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection contains reports relating to global implications of terrorist activities, guerrilla operations, and regional conflicts throughout the world. Most reports were written by Yossef Bodansky, who served as Director of the House Republican Research Committee Task Force on Terrorism and Unconventional Warfare of the U.S. House of Representatives from 1988 to 2004. The reports are organized chronologically.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Terrorism.; Guerrillas.; World politics--1989-.; United States--Foreign relations.
Collection Contents
- 1. Table of contents (Folder 1: 1)
- 2. "Trends in Afghanistan,", 28 July 1989 (Folder 1: 1)
- 3. "Arab Extremists in Afghanistan,", 2 and 10 August 1989 (Folder 1: 1)
- 4. "The Strategic Ramifications of the War in Afghanistan,", 2 August 1989 (Folder 1: 1)
- 5. "The Indian Military Involvement in Afghanistan,", 2 August 1989 (Folder 1: 1)
- 6. "Sheikh Obeid's Ideology,", circa August 1989 (Folder 1: 1)
- 7. "Soviet Political Assassinations and Terrorism,", 28 August 1989 (Folder 1: 1)
- 8. "The CIA Has Bungled It,", by Bill McCollum, Washington Post, 10 September 1989 (Folder 1: 1)
- 9. "The Intensification of the Struggle for Southern Africa,", circa September 1989 (Folder 1: 1)
- 10. "The build-up of the Afghan Armed Forces,", 10 October 1989 (Folder 1: 1)
- 11. "Cuba, Nicaragua and Salvador,", November 1989 (Folder 1: 2)
- 12. "Escalation in Angola,", 12 January 1990 (Folder 1: 2)
- 13. "Escalation in Laos: Vietnamese Warfare Against the Hmong and Lowland Lao Resistance,", 31 January 1990 (Folder 1: 2)
- 14. "Update of the Situation in Angola,", 2 February, 1889 (Folder 1: 2)
- 15. "Intensification of the FAPLA Offensive in Angola,", 4 February 1990 (Folder 1: 2)
- 16. "Seize the Moment, Avoid a New Vietnam,", by Richard M. Nixon, Los Angeles Times, 1 February 1990 (Folder 1: 2)
- 17. "The Flight of Mavinga,", 16 February 1990 (Folder 1: 2)
- 18. "The Return of Peter the Great - a Grand Overview of the Evolving Soviet global strategy,", 22 February 1990 (Folder 1: 2)
- 19. "A Question of Trust,", 1 March 1990 (Folder 1: 2)
- 20. "A Question of Trust - Was There Soviet Disinformation?" 6 March 1990 (Folder 1: 3)
- 21. "Angola - After the Fall of Mavinga,", 13 March 1990 (Folder 1: 3)
- 22. "Tanai's Coup in Kabul,", 15 March 1990 (Folder 1: 4)
- 23. "Soviet Advisers Appear to Play Major Role in Afghanistan," Soviet/East European Report, Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, Vol. VII, No. 20, 1 March 1990 (Folder 1: 4)
- 24. "The Soviet "Peace" Dividend,", 22 March 1990 (Folder 1: 4)
- 25. "Hungary 1956 - Czechoslovakia 1968 - Lithuania 1990?", 2 March 1990 (Folder 1: 4)
- 26. "The Soviet Armed Forces in Central Asia,", 31 March 1990 (Folder 1: 4)
- 27. "Pitfalls in Policy on the Path to Kabul," by Richard Mackenzie, Insight, 9 April 1990 (Folder 1: 4)
- 28. "Qaddafi is Back in Business,", 15 April 1990 (Folder 1: 4)
- 29. "Pakistan's Afghan Army,", 17 April 1990 (Folder 1: 4)
- 30. The Vietnam War: 1990,", 25 April 1990 (Folder 1: 4)
- 31. "Between the Tiger and the Crocodile: U.S. Policy in Southern Asia,", 4 May 1990 (Folder 1: 4)
- A. "Islamabad's Grim View of the Future,", 19 June 1990 (Folder 1: 5)
- B. "Cambodia - Who's Who in the Resistance,", 19 June 1990 (Folder 1: 5)
- C. "Status Report on Cambodia - an Update,", 12 June 1990 (Folder 1: 5)
- D. "The Political Realities of Southeast Asia,", 23 July 1990 (Folder 1: 5)
- E. "Kuwait and Iraq's Territorial Aspiration,", 25 July 1990 (Folder 1: 5)
- F. "The Near East After the Invasion of Kuwait,", 9 August 1990 (Folder 1: 5)
- G. "Emerging Trends in the Persian Gulf Crisis August 20 1990,", 20 August 1990 (Folder 1: 6)
- H. "Saddam Hussein's Game,", 28 August 1990 (Folder 1: 6)
- I. "The Soviet Union's Support for the Iraqi Invasion,", 6 September 1990 (Folder 1: 6)
- J. "Iraq's Western Theater,", 10 September 1990 (Folder 1: 6)
- K. "The Role of Iran and Syria in the Persian Gulf Crisis,", 17 September 1990 (Folder 1: 6)
- L. "Saddam Hussein,", 3 October 1990 (Folder 1: 6)
- M. "Iraq's Other Bomb,", 28 November 1990 (Folder 1: 7)
- N. "The Rise of Popular Fundamentalism,", 4 December 1990 (Folder 1: 7)
- O. "Libya - Between the Persian Gulf and West Africa,", 17 December 1990 (Folder 1: 7)
- P. "Laos Defines Its Future,", 2 January 1991 (Folder 1: 7)
- Q. "Putting Shevardnadze's Resignation in Context,", 9 January 1990 (Folder 1: 7)
- R. "Lenin Is Always With Us,", 6 February 1991 (Folder 1: 7)
- S. "War and aftermath: the Soviet-Iraqi maneuvers,", 25 February 1991 (Folder 1: 7)
- T. "War and Aftermath - Part II,", 27 February 1991 (Folder 1: 8)
- U. "The Bear at Sea,", 1 March 1991 (Folder 1: 8)
- V. "Iran Escalates its Direct Involvement in Iraq,", 22 March 1991 (Folder 1: 8)
- W. "A Time of Decision in Iraq and Iran,", 28 March 1991 (Folder 1: 8)
- XYZ. "Cambodia - Update,", 8 April 1991 (Folder 1: 8)
- AA. "Jordan - the Center of Sunni Islamist Terrorism,", 11 April 1991 (Folder 1: 9)
- BB. "Cambodia - Update 2,", 15 April 1991 (Folder 1: 9)
- CC. "The New World Order:"Put-up or Shut-up,", 23 April 1991 (Folder 1: 9)
- DD. "Vietnam: International Terrorism and Revolutionary Warfare,", 20 May 1991 (Folder 1: 10)
- "The Long Fuse - One Year After the Gulf War,", 29 July 1991 (Folder 1: 10)
- "Israel and Paradox of the American Peace Initiative,", 29 July 1991 (Folder 1: 10)
- "Iran's Nuclear Effort - Update,", 29 July 1991 (Folder 1: 10)
- "Narco-Terrorism and the Syrian Connection,", 13 August 1991 (Folder 1: 10)
- "BCCI (Bank of Credit and Commerce International) - Between Peru and Washington, D.C.,", 10 September 1991 (Folder 1: 10)
- "BCCI and the Financing of Terrorism,", 7 October 1991 (Folder 1: 10)
- "BCCI and Nuclear Question,", 28 October 1991 (Folder 1: 10)
- "Confronting the Pax Americana,", 5 November 1991 (Folder 1: 10)
- "Yugoslavia's Support for Terrorism,", 12 November 12 1991 (Folder 1: 10)
- "Inside Iran- an Introduction,", 25 November 1991 (Folder 1: 10)
- "China and the Arms Race in the Middle East,", circa December 1991 (Folder 1: 10)
- "The Mideast Peace Progress: How it Works,", January 1992 (Folder 1: 10)
- "Armenia,", 6 January 1992 (Folder 1: 10)
- "Libyan Terrorism,", 7 January 1992 (Folder 1: 10)
- "Iran's Strategy and Nuclear Capabilities,", 20 January 1992 (Folder 1: 12)
- "The Situation Inside Libya,", 27 January 1992 (Folder 1: 12)
- "Iran's Shadow over the Red Sea,", 3 February 1992 (Folder 1: 12)
- "The Hezbollah After Abbas Mussawi,", 24 February 1992 (Folder 1: 12)
- "The China Syndrome: China and North Korea's Strategic Export Campaign,", 9 March 1992 (Folder 1: 12)
- "North Korean Weapons of Mass Destruction: a Brief Overview,", 11 March 1992 (Folder 1: 12)
- "Sudan: Up-date,", 30 March 1992 (Folder 1: 12)
- "Iran's Nuclear Weapons - Update II,", 30 April 1992 (Folder 1: 12)
- "Iran's Evolving Persian Gulf Strategy,", 10 November 1992 (Folder 1: 13)
- "Europe, Serbia, and the Iraqi Connection,", 9 September 1992 (Folder 1: 13)
- "Transfer of Power in Pyongyang,", 25 August 1992 (Folder 1: 13)
- "Iran's European Springboard? 3 September 1992" (Folder 1: 13)
- "Tehran, Bagdad and Damascus: the New Axis Pact,", 10 August 1992 (Folder 1: 13)
- "The Islamist Threat in Somalia,", 4 January 1993 (Folder 1: 14)
- "Air Defense Forces in the Former Yugoslavia,", 20 July 1993 (Folder 1: 14)
- "The North Korean Nuclear Weapons,", 14 July 1993 (Folder 1: 14)
- "The New Nuclear Smuggling System,", 7 June 1993 (Folder 1: 14)
- "Major Events and Conferences in Islamist Terrorism,", 13 July 1993 (Folder 1: 14)
- "Note on Terrorism Roster,", 14 September 1993 (Folder 1: 14)
- "Somalia Up-date,", 21 November 1993 (Folder 1: 14)
- "Islam Against the Church,", 19 January 1994 (Folder 1: 15)
- "Iran Against the Church II: the Case of Bishop Hayk Hovsepian,", 7 February 1994 (Folder 1: 15)
- "U.S. Troops on Golan 'Quicksand?'" by Mark Langfan, reprinted from January-March 1994 issue of Security Affairs (Folder 1: 15)
- "Kim Jong-Il: the New Enigma,", 13 July 1994 (Folder 1: 15)
- "Pyongyang and the U.S. Nuclear Gambit,", 11 August 1994 (Folder 1: 15)
- "Pakistan's Nuclear Brinkmanship,", 24 August 1994 (Folder 1: 15)
- "Some Background: the U.S.-North Korea Agreement,", 19 October 1994 (Folder 1: 15)